If your marriage is having challenges, don't give up! Ask God.
Don't let challenges quit you; let God.
Your business - don't let challenges quit you.
Your marriage - challenges should not quit you.
Your relationships - challenges should not quit you.
If you allow challenges to quit you. you are destroyed.
You are running from strength. You are running from grace, more grace.
Don't let challenges quit you but God. God should say leave, not challenges.
You abandon your marriage because of challenges.
You abandon your business partner because of challenges.
Don't let challenges quit you, but God.
Challenges are a grace to strengthen, help and equip you more.
When you are in the midst of challenges, ask God whether to quit or not -
not for that challenge to quit you.
No matter what they say about your wife or husband. Don't let it quit your marriage.
You quit your village because of witches and wizards.
Many of you that are here now - you abandoned your village because of witches and wizards.
You left your husband. You divorced because of challenges.
Everywhere are challenges.
You should see challenges as a blessing, not enemy.
See challenges as a blessing, not an enemy.
See me - my challenges turned to blessings.
Say with me, "My challenges turned to blessings".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank You, Lord.
Viewers, take this: Don't quit your marriage because of challenges.
Challenges could be this, could be that. Whatever they say about your wife or your husband -
your husband is this, your husband is a womanizer, your wife is a womanizer -
all challenges, situation.
Whatever they say, don't quit your marriage. Ask God.
In every situation, God has something to say.
If you ask God, "God, with this situation now, what will I do?" - God will tell you what to do.
Sometimes, these challenges are blessings to strengthen marriage or relationships.
When you see a wonderful relationship or great marriage today,
ask them and they will tell you how many times great challenges came.
They refused to quit but today, they are role-models.
"Ah, I love that husband and wife. I love them. Look at their home - wonderful!"
Ask them what they have gone through. They will tell you a story that you could not bear.
A story that divorced your marriage. A story that separated you from your relationship.
But yet, they stand together.
50% of us here are a good example of what I'm talking about.
You know before now, some years in the past, your impression about T.B. Joshua was so bad.
Many of you were asked to pray against me, in your different meetings.
But I refused to pray against you because I knew you will be coming here one day.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you were asking God to bind me, to loose me, to bind me, to loose me -
there is nothing you have not said in your fasting and prayer, but I kept quiet
because I knew you would be coming. You are welcome.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let's assume while you were binding me, loosing me, I too was standing here to loose you, to bind you.
If you could not bind me, I would have bound you.
If you could not loose me, I would have loosed you.
If you could not deliver me, I would have delivered you. Something would have happened.
You take a stone, you throw it at me
If I show you many stones - your own stones, I stored them.
Instead of taking it and throwing it back, I said, "No, I will not throw this stone back".
I kept the stone because I knew you would be coming back here.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know, it's a stone you are throwing when you say,
"Lord Jesus, Lord Jesus, this man is a devil, is this..."
You are throwing stones and each stone bounces in front of me.
I look at it. God says, "No, don't throw it back!"
Assume I throw the stone back - if you cannot deliver me, I will deliver you.
But today, you are here. This is a good example of what I'm talking about.
You destroy relationships beyond repair.
When people offend you, your attitude, your behavior -
you curse the person to the extent that that relationship will not be repaired again.
That is exactly what many of you are going through now.
When you know that this person that is bad now can be the best tomorrow, you will take precaution.
Do you know that someone who is satan today to you, can be your saviour tomorrow?
I don't destroy relationships beyond repair.
If I have you as a friend, no matter what you have done to me,
I will make sure I will not destroy that relationship beyond repair.
because I know tomorrow, you may be my saviour.
Brother, come. See my brother here.
No matter if I am a friend to my brother here - we are very close friends -
no matter what happens between us, no matter what the attempt,
if I learn that he is trying to murder me, to kill me, to destroy me and God protects me,
I will make sure that that relationship will not be destroyed through me beyond repair
because I know tomorrow, this man may be there for me.
But if I now, because of what this man wants to do to me and God protects me,
I now begin to fight back beyond repair,
I will not be able to have this opportunity in the future, tomorrow.
But today, you destroy relationships beyond repair because of situations, challenges, conflicts.
Tell your neighbour, "You have been destroying your relationships with people beyond repair,
because of conflicts, trouble and challenges.
You have been destroying your relationships with people beyond repair".
You can fight but be conscious that the person you are fighting may be your saviour tomorrow.
Don't destroy that relationship beyond what? - Repair.
This is the situation many of you find yourself in today. All of you. All.
There are many people you know - very very great and they were very close to you.
They were your enemy in the past.
Because of fight, you used your hand to destroy that relationship beyond repair.
Today, you can't just have that goal to meet them.
Even marriage, your former husband - you divorced and separated -
that relationship should not be destroyed beyond repair.
That is your former marriage and you divorced, you left the marriage.
That man can be someone who is your saviour tomorrow.
You woman too can be a saviour to that man tomorrow.
I am a good example. People have destroyed their relationship with me beyond repair.
Today, imagine I stand here and say, "Hey, praise the Lord. That man is devil, he is evil spirit.
He drinks blood. he did that...".
If you now see me with the man tomorrow, how will you feel?
The church is scattered. You will leave my church.
"T.B - you said yesterday that the man is a devil. You said the man drinks blood.
You are now flirting with the man. It means you people are drinking blood together."
That is the problem. This is why I'm just alone here.
Imagine I stand here to say, "Hey, that church is devil, that church drinks blood, that man is not good.
That man is this, that man is that". - I have said it, and all of you know. And it is televised on Emmanuel TV.
So, if you now see me with the man I said is drinking blood, is a devil,
you know he is a devil, you can bet it, and you now see me tomorrow with the man,
will you still be a member of my church?
Ah! You have to leave because we are drinking blood together.
That is, destroy relationships beyond repair.
That is the life I live.
When I know the argument is too hot, I keep quiet
because I don't want to destroy the relationship beyond repair.
That is why people, the whole world says, "T. B. Joshua will not reply".
That is the slogan people say - "Ah, that man will not talk."
If you say, "T.B. Joshua is this, is that", no matter what you say about T.B. Joshua, he will not talk.
The reason is that I don't want to destroy any relationship beyond repair
because the man I'm fighting may be my saviour tomorrow.
So, it's better I should choose the side of silence.
If I remain silent, you don't know what is in my mind. I will just remain silent.
This is why the noise everywhere, they say, "He is not replying, he is not this" - I will not talk
because the man that is fighting me, the man that wants me to die may be my saviour tomorrow.
Tomorrow is mystery.
So, I don't want to destroy that relationship.
If tomorrow he is my saviour, I can still walk majestically towards him.
I will tell him, "I never said anything when you were abusing me. I never said anything.
Quote me, what did I say?" He will say, "You never said anything".
"Ok, let the relationship continue."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I think this will help you in many things you have in court - going to court, sueing this, that.
Many things you say, 'over your dead body', your former wife, your former husband,
whatever he might have done to you yesterday, whatever -
I think you can still look to see what you can quickly do.
If you say you are too big, what of your children?
If I say, "I'm too big to be helped", what of my children?
The person who wants me to die can be my children's saviour tomorrow.
Madam, you are crying. Come. What happened?
Man of God, I am going through that situation.
I have been so hurt so much by...
Don't worry. Sit down. The message really touched her.
She cannot bear it again and started crying, saying, "Ah! Oh! This message is talking to me!"
Please, don't destroy relationships beyond repair. Tell your neighbour.
[Don't destroy relationships beyond repair.]
Tell your neighbour again.
Tell your neighbour, please.
[Don't destroy relationships beyond repair.]
Stand up and say it to yourself.
Tell viewers all over the world.
[Don't destroy relationships beyond repair.]
I can't hear you.
Again and again.
[Don't destroy relationships beyond repair.]
That's all.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When there is a hot argument, look at the person who is after you.
He may be the saviour tomorrow.
You may be seated. Thank you. Hallelujah.
TT: Monica Asefa 13/07/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 18/07/2018